RG 069:133, Marilyn P.A. Seichter Collection
Seichter (Marilyn P.A.) Collection
Connecticut State Library
Marilyn P.A. Seichter collection
1945-2002,
bulk 1959-1994
Connecticut State Library
Seichter, Marilyn P.A.
8 cubic feet
Marilyn P.A. Seichter (1945-2002), the first woman to graduate from the University of Connecticut School of Law, specialized in the fields of women's rights and family law. She served as the first women president of the Connecticut Bar Association among other posts.
RG069_133
2006-040
Biographical Note
Marilyn P.A. Seichter was born on May 23, 1945 in Wallingford, Connecticut. Growing up she attended Holy Trinity School and graduated in 1963 from Lyman Hall High School, both located in Wallingford. She then went on to pursue her undergraduate degree at the University of Connecticut, majoring in Political Science and becoming active in student government. After graduating in 1967 she attended the University of Connecticut School of Law from 1969 to 1970, becoming one of a first women to obtain a law degree from that institution. In the fall of 1970 Seichter joined the law firm of Hyman, Cantor and Klau, eventually rising to partner in the firm that was renamed to Hyman, Cantor, Seichter, and Klau. Seichter specialized in the fields of women's rights and family law. She worked on Abele v. Markle ("Women v. Connecticut"), the case that overturned Connecticut's law prohibiting abortion prior to the Supreme Court decision in Roe v. Wade. She also successfully represented the National Organization for Women (NOW) in a suit filed against 35 newspapers to stop the practice of segregated newspaper ads for men and women. She became friends of Ella T. Grasso and worked on Grasso's gubernatorial campaign. Seichter became the first woman chairperson of the Connecticut Ethics Commission, the first woman president of the Connecticut Bar Association (1989-1990) and had served as chair of the Young Lawyers Section (1980-1981), president of the Hartford Local Unit of the Young Lawyers Section, chair of the Marriage and Family Counseling and Conciliation Committee, delegate to the House of Delegates, and a member of the Mediation and Arbitration Executive Committee of the American Bar Association. She also served as president of the New England Bar Association (1991-1992), president of the Connecticut Women's Education and Legal Fund, and was a member of the Governor's Ad Hoc Committee on Judicial Selection and the Committee on the Status of Women. She died on February 10, 2002 from Huntington's disease.
Scope and Content
The collection includes middle and high school materials, University of Connecticut undergraduate materials, University of Connecticut Law School materials, materials from her professional career and association with Ella Grasso. The range of materials includes correspondence, news clippings, publications, awards, photographs, and memorabilia.
Arrangement
Series 1. Middle and High School materials (1954-1963) contains autograph books, college acceptance letters, correspondence, diplomas, graduation material, memorabilia, photographs of classmates, report cards, and a yearbook.
Series 2. University of Connecticut Undergraduate materials (1963-1968) contains calendars, correspondence, course grades, a diploma, graduation material, law school recommendation and acceptance letters. Memorabilia, news clippings, photographs, student government material, student identification cards, and a yearbook.
Series 3. University of Connecticut Law School materials (1968-1970) contains correspondence, course material, a diploma, event material, graduation material, news clippings and publications.
Series 4. Professional Career (1970-2002) contains admission certificates to the Connecticut Bar, the U.S. District Court of Connecticut, and to the U.S. Court of Appeals for the Second Circuit, awards, and material related to the Connecticut Bar Association, Ethics Commission, New England Bar Association, Committee on the Status of Women and the Women v. Connecticut lawsuit. Also included are a small amount of papers related to case work, general correspondence, news clippings, programs and publications.
Series 5. Ella Grasso material (1973-1987) contains materials related to Grasso's gubernatorial campaign, her inaugurations, her memorial service and statue, and photographs.
Series 6. Personal documents (1945-1988) Contains Seichter's birth certificate, working paper, and a manuscript autobiography.
Series 7. Photographs (1945-1994) contains photographs of Seichter, including one with Geraldine Ferraro, and one with Connecticut Supreme Court Chief Justice Ellen Peters taken in the courtroom, as well as baby photographs and studio photographs.
Series 8. Memorabilia (1963-1996).
Series 9. Oversize contains oversize material separated from other series.
Related Material
, Connecticut State Library.
Index Terms
Subjects:
Women lawyers--Connecticut
Persons:
Seichter, Marilyn P.A.; Grasso, Ella
Places:
Wallingford (Conn.)
Occupations:
Lawyers
Document Types:
Autograph albums; Certificates; Clippings; Correspondence; Diplomas; Memorabilia; Photographs; Publications; School yearbooks; Scrapbooks
Restrictions on Access
These records are stored at an off-site facility and therefore may not be available on a same-day basis.
See the policy.
Provenance
Marilyn Seichter assembled this collection herself. The Connecticut State Library obtained it from her nephew Daniel Seichter on June 15, 2006.
Container List
- Series 1. Middle and High School Material, 1954-1963
  - Autograph books, 1954-1959, undated (Box 1)
  - College acceptance letters, 1963 February 8-20 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1956-1961, undated (Box 1)
  - Diplomas (Box 1)
    - Holy Trinity School, 1959 (Box 1)
    - Lyman Hall High School, 1963 (Box 1)
  - Graduation (Box 1)
    - Holy Trinity School, 1959 (Box 1)
    - Lyman Hall High School, 1963 June 11-14, undated (Box 1)
  - Memorabilia, 1960-1963, undated (Box 1)
  - New clippings, 1960-1963, undated (Box 1)
  - Photographs, 1963, undated (Box 1)
  - Report cards, test scores and schedules (Box 1)
    - Holy Trinity School, 1958 (Box 1)
    - Lyman Hall High School, 1959-1963 (Box 1)
  - Yearbook, 1963 (Box 1)
- Series 2. University of Connecticut Undergraduate Material, 1963-1968
  - Calendars, 1963-1965 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence, 1963-1968, undated (Box 2)
  - Course grades, 1964-1967 (Box 2)
  - Diploma, 1967 June 12 (Box 2)
  - Graduation, 1967 June 13 (Box 2)
  - Law school recommendation and acceptance letters, 1967 April-May (Box 2)
  - Memorabilia, 1963-1965, undated (Box 2)
  - News clippings, 1963-1966, undated (Box 2)
  - Photographs, 1964-1967, undated (Box 2)
  - Student Government (Box 2)
    - General, 1964 October 12, undated (Box 2)
    - Campaign materials, undated (Box 2)
      - Student Government President campaign banner, undated; In oversize (Box 13)
    - Congratulatory letters, 1966 October 17-30, undated (Box 2)
    - News clippings, 1963-1966, undated (Box 2)
  - Student identification cards, 1963-1966 (Box 2)
  - Yearbook, 1967 (Box 3)
- Series 3. University of Connecticut School of Law Material, 1968-1970
  - Certificate from Board of Student Public Defenders and Legal Assistants, undated (Box 4)
  - Correspondence, 1968-1970, undated (Box 4)
  - Course work, research, grades and schedules, 1968-1969, undated (Box 4)
  - Diploma, 1970 June 1 (Box 4)
  - Events, Events, 1968-1970 (Box 4)
  - Graduation, 1970 May 31 (Box 4)
  - The Legal Realist, 1968-1970 (Box 4)
  - News clippings, 1970, undated (Box 4)
  - Printed materials, 1967-1970 (Box 4)
  - The Starr Report, 1967-1968 (Box 4)
- Series 4. Professional Career, 1970-2002; bulk, 1970-1994
  - Admission certificates, 1970-1971; In oversize (Box 13)
  - Announcement and business card, undated (Box 5)
  - Awards and certificates, 1970-1994 (Box 5)
  - Awards
    - American Bar Association Young Lawyers Division, 1979-1980 (Box 9)
    - American Bar Association Family Law Merit Certificate, 1982 August 11 (Box 9)
    - Connecticut Bar Association Recognition as President, 1989-1990 (Box 9)
    - Invitation to dinner in honor of Marilyn Seichter, 1993 October 21 (Box 9)
    - Connecticut Bar Association John Eldred Shields Memorial Award, 1994 June 6 (Box 9)
    - University of Connecticut Law School Appreciation of Service, undated; 2 items (Box 9)
    - Connecticut Bar Association Chairperson of Young Lawyers Division, 1980-1981 (Box 10)
    - Congressional Record, 1993 October 15 (Box 10)
    - Congressional Record, 1993 October 21 (Box 10)
    - Connecticut General Assembly Official Citation in recognition of achievements, 1993 October 21 (Box 10)
  - Case work, 1972-1994 (Box 5)
  - Connecticut Bar Association (Box 5)
    - Annual dinners, 1982-1994 (Box 5)
    - Annual meetings, 1990-1994 (Box 5)
    - Annual reports, 1981-1993 (Box 5)
    - Connecticut Lawyer, 1980-1990 (Box 5)
  - Correspondence, 1971-1993 (Box 5)
  - Ethics Commission (Box 5)
    - General, 1977-1978 (Box 5)
    - News clippings, 1977-1978, undated (Box 5)
    - Official Statement from Gov. John G. Rowland, 2002 (Box 5)
  - New England Bar Association, undated (Box 5)
  - News clippings, 1970-1991, undated (Box 6)
  - Programs, 1983-1995, undated (Box 6)
  - Publications (Box 6)
    - Bar Leader, 1989-1990 (Box 6)
    - The Connecticut Law Tribune, 1989-1996 (Box 6)
  - Status of Women, Committee on the (Box 6)
    - Correspondence, 1970-1971 (Box 6)
  - Women v. Connecticut (Box 6)
    - Correspondence, 1970-1972 (Box 6)
    - Legal documents, 1972 May-June, undated (Box 6)
    - News clippings, 1972-1973, undated (Box 6)
    - Scrapbook, 1970-1973; In oversize (Box 13)
- Series 5. Ella Grasso Material, 1973-1987
  - Gubernatorial Campaign
    - Correspondence, 1973-1974 (Box 6)
    - Election results, 1978 (Box 6)
    - Issues, 1973-1974 (Box 6)
    - News clippings, 1974 February-October, undated (Box 7)
    - News clippings about gubernatorial candidate Robert H. Steele, 1974 July-September (Box 7)
    - Press materials, 1974 November 4, undated (Box 7)
    - Press releases, 1974 August (Box 7)
  - Inaugural Ball, 1975 January, undated (Box 7)
  - Memorial service and statue, 1981-1987 (Box 7)
  - Photographs, undated (Box 7)
- Series 6. Personal Documents, 1945-1988
  - Autobiographical sketch, 1988, undated (Box 8)
  - Birth certificate, 1945 May 23 (Box 8)
  - Journal entry, 1983 June 24 (Box 8)
  - Working paper, 1962 January 22 (Box 8)
- Series 7. Photographs, 1945-1994
  - General, undated (Box 8)
  - Marilyn Seichter (Box 8)
    - General, 1994, undated (Box 8)
    - Baby photographs, 1945-1946, undated (Box 8)
    - Negatives, undated (Box 8)
    - Studio photographs, 1982, undated (Box 8)
    - Ocean State Marathon, 1980; Separate oversize item (Box 8)
- Series 8. Memorabilia, 1963-1996
  - General, 1963-1982 (Box 8)
  - Cards and envelopes, 1963-1996 (Box 8)
  - Tassels, undated (Box 8)
  - Theatre playbills and tickets, 1960-1965, undated (Box 8)
  - Hartford Young Lawyers President, 1975-1977 (Box 11)
  - Young Lawyers Division Cross Country, 1978 (Box 11)
  - Connecticut Bar Association President gavel, 1989-1990 (Box 11)
  - Connecticut Bar Association President plate, 1989-1990 (Box 11)
  - New England Bar Association 20th Anniversary paperweight, 1989 (Box 11)
  - New England Bar Association President gavel, 1991-1992 (Box 11)
  - Flag depicting a whale, undated (Box 11)
  - C.A.L.S. marble paperweight, undated (Box 11)
  - "1st Woman to head bar group", Hartford Courant, 1989 May 23 (Box 12)
  - "Wallingford lawyer heads state bar", (Meriden) Record-Journal, 1989 June 14 (Box 12)
  - "State Bar Association Names First Woman, Youngest President", Glastonbury Citizen, 1989 June 29 (Box 12)
- Series 9. Oversize (Box 13)